A Guide to John Henry Ingram's Poe Collection
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Part Four: Printed Matter from Magazines, Newspapers, and Books (Box 9)
  - " EDGAR ALLEN [sic] POE, " a letter to the Editor by "A Correspondent of Poe.", 1881 ca. March 16.; [800]; 1/4 column clipped from the Great West (Box 14)
    A defense of Poe against criticism by a Mr. Rothaker in the New York Tribune.
  - INGRAM'S AND STEDMAN'S WORK ON POE, unsigned, 1881 March 26.; [801]; Paragraph clipped from the Newcastle-upon-Tyne Chronicle (Box 14)
    Favorable comments.
  - "THE MEMORY OF POE," unsigned, 1881 March 27.; [802]; 4 columns clipped from the New York Herald (Box 14)
    Publishes letters by and about Poe to Dr. Joseph E. Snodgrass. These letters were found by Mrs. Snodgrass after her husband's death in 1880 and lent by her to William H. Carpenter, Editor of the Baltimore Sun. Carpenter allowed William Hand Browne to make transcripts and press copies of them for Ingram and himself, and he, in turn, loaned his press copies to Edward Spencer who edited them for printing in the New York Herald.
  - ANNOUNCEMENT OF THE SECOND ENTERTAINMENT TO BE HELD FOR THE POE MEMORIAL FUND ON 23 APRIL, unsigned, 1881 April 3.; [803]; 1/2 column clipped from the New York Times. (Box 14)
  - "POE ON POE," unsigned, 1881 April 4.; [804]; 1/2 column clipped from the Baltimore American (Box 14)
    An additional letter from Poe to Dr. Joseph E. Snodgrass, 1 April 1841, found by Mrs. Snodgrass after she had lent the first nine to the editor of the Baltimore Sun.
  - "POE IN HIS OWN DEFENCE," unsigned, 1881 April 4.; [805]; 1/2 column clipped from the Baltimore American (Box 14)
    Notes that the recently published letter of 1 April 1841 does much to vindicate Poe from charges of drunkenness during that period of his life.
  - "POE AND BURTON," unsigned, 1881 April.; [806]; 1/2 column clipped from the New York World (Box 14)
    Prints Poe's letter to Dr. Joseph E. Snodgrass of 1 April 1841.
  - " EDGAR ALLAN POE'S HABITS," unsigned, 1881 April 4.; [807]; 1/2 column clipped from an unidentified New York newspaper (Box 14)
  - "POE'S DEFENSE OF HIMSELF," unsigned, 1881 ca. April 5.; [808]; 1/2 column clipped from an unidentified newspaper, reprinted from the Baltimore American (Box 14)
    Prints portions of Poe's letter to Dr. Joseph E. Snodgrass of 1 April 1841.
  - " EDGAR POE, " letter to the Editor by Dr. William Gibbon Carter, 1881 ca. April 6.; [809]; Paragraph clipped from the Richmond Dispatch (Box 14)
    Poe's friend and physician agrees with Poe's declaration in his letter to Dr. Joseph E. Snodgrass of 1 April 1841 that he was not a drunkard: "dress Poe in rags, and the gentleman is there."
  - "THE POE MEMORIAL," unsigned, 1881 April 17.; [810]; 1/2 column clipped from and unidentified newspaper (Box 14)
    The New York Academy of Music plans another entertainment to raise money for the Poe memorial in New York City. Nearly $3000 has already been raised by two entertainments: one at the Madison Square Theater, another at Booth's Theater.
  - ACTIVITIES AND DIFFICULTIES OF THE POE MEMORIAL COMMITTEE, unsigned, 1881 ca. April 20.; [811]; 3 clippings from unidentified newspapers pasted on a strip of paper (Box 14)
  - "THE POE FESTIVAL," unsigned, 1881 ca. April 23.; [812]; 1/2 column clipped from an unidentified New York newspaper (Box 14)
    Report of the benefit entertainment for the Poe memorial which was held at the New York Academy of Music.
  - "RETURNED TO DUST," unsigned, 1881 April 26.; [813]; 1/2 column clipped from the Richmond Dispatch (Box 14)
    Obituary of Louisa Gabriella Allan (Mrs. John Allan ), who died on Sunday, 24 April, and was buried on Monday, 25 April.
  - "DEATH OF MRS. ALLAN," unsigned, 1881 April 26.; [814]; Paragraph clipped from the Richmond State (Box 14)
    Obituary of Louisa Gabriella Allan (Mrs. John Allan ).
  - LETTERS TO THE EDITOR CONCERNING POE, by "J. C. L." and Edward A. Oldham, 1881 April 27.; [815]; 1/2 column clipped from the Richmond State (Box 14)
    "J. C. L." corrects statements about Poe's history that were printed in the State's obituary of Mrs. Allan. Oldham requests names and addresses of those living who attended West Point with Poe.
  - "A FEW WORDS OF EXPLANATION FROM DR. CLOVER," letter to the Editor, 1881 April 28.; [816]; 1/4 column clipped from the Richmond Dispatch (Box 14)
    Dr. Clover makes several corrections in the obituary of Mrs. Allan.
  - " EDGAR ALLAN POE, " letter to the Editor by Colonel Thomas H. Ellis, 1881 May 7.; [817]; 3 columns clipped from the Richmond Standard (Box 14)
    Ellis' letter is essentially a eulogy to Louisa Gabriella Allan (Mrs. John Allan ).
  - "CONCERNING POE'S BIRTHPLACE," letter to the Editor, unsigned, 1882 January 25?.; [818]; Paragraph clipped from the Richmond State (Box 14)
    Raises the question of where Poe was born: Boston or Baltimore ?
  - ON DR. JOHN J. MORAN'S ACCOUNT OF POE'S DEATH, unsigned, 1882 April 12.; [819]; Paragraph clipped from the Washington Evening Critic (Box 14)
    Suggests that there is some question about Moran's motives in waiting so long to give his account of Poe's death, so long that everyone else who knew the circumstances is now dead.
  - REVIEW OF ANDREW LANG, EDITOR, THE POEMS OF EDGAR ALLAN POE, WITH AN ESSAY, "THE POETRY OF EDGAR ALLAN POE, " BY ANDREW LANG, unsigned, 1882 May 13.; [820]; 1 1/2 columns clipped from the Academy (Box 14)
  - "IN DEFENCE OF POE," unsigned, 1882 May 28.; [821]; 1 1/4 columns clipped from the Spartanburg Carolinian (SC), reprinted from the Baltimore American (Box 14)
    Report of Dr. John J. Moran's lectures on Poe at the YMCA Hall.
  - "TIT-BITS FROM THE WORKS OF EDGAR ALLAN POE, " unsigned, 1882 July 29.; [822]; Pp. 236-237 clipped from Tit-Bits (Box 14)
    Excerpts from some of Poe's tales and from "Marginalia."
  - "RECENSIONEN," unsigned, 1882 August 15.; [823]; Pp. 3-4 clipped from Das Telephon (Box 14)
    In German. Discusses Poe and Thomas Carlyle.
  - " EDGAR ALLAN POE, " by Eduard Engel, post 1882.; [824]; Pp. 157-160, 169-172, parts II and III, clipped from Das Magazin fuer die Literatur des Inund Auslandes, No. 13 (Box 14)
    In German.
  - REVIEW OF A. WINTERFIELD'S TRANSLATION OF POE'S WEIRD TALES ["UNHEIMLICH GESCHICHTEN"] INTO GERMAN, by E. E. [ Eduard Engel ], post 1882.; [825]; Pp. 689-690 clipped from Magazin fuer die Literatur des Auslandes, No. 44 (Box 14)
  - "THE SHAVIN' (A PIECE OF RAVIN' A LA EDGAR A. POE )," by John F. Mill, 1882 February 10.; [826]; 5 6-line stanzas clipped from an unidentified newspaper (Box 14)
    This parody was sent to Ingram by P. J. Mullin [Item 369] who claimed that he first saw it in a Scottish magazine entitled the People's Friend.
  - REVIEW OF CONTES GROTESQUES BY POE, TRANSLATED BY MILE HENNEQUIN, by Emile Bergerat, 1882 March 6.; [827]; 6 1/4 columns clipped from Le Voltaire (Box 14)
    In French.
  - "SOME NEW MEMORIES OF POE," by Melville Phillips, 1882 May 26.; [828]; 5 1/4 columns clipped from Texas Siftings (Box 14)
    Recollections of Poe told to Phillips by John Sartain. Freely annotated by Ingram with comments such as, "Full of self-evident lies."
  - " EDGAR ALLAN POE'S HOME," unsigned, 1882 June 10.; [829]; 1/4 column clipped from the New York Times (Box 14)
    The cottage at Fordham sold at auction to Milton [Nelson?] Strang for $5,700.
  - " EDGAR POE'S COTTAGE," unsigned, 1882 June 10.; [830]; 1/2 column clipped from the New York Herald (Box 14)
    The cottage at Fordham was sold at auction to Nelson [Milton?] Strang for $7,000. A neighbor of the Poes reminisces about the family when they lived there.
  - " EDGAR ALLAN POE, " by B. Montgomerie Ranking, 1882 September.; [831]; Pp. 352-360 clipped from Time; A Monthly Magazine, Vol. IX (Box 14)
    A defence of Poe's personal and literary reputations.
  - REVIEW OF THE RAVEN, BY POE, ILLUSTRATED BY GUSTAVE DOR, WITH A COMMENT UPON THE POEM BY EDMUND CLARENCE STEDMAN, unsigned, 1882 November 3.; [832]; 3/4 column clipped from the Academy (Box 14)
  - PROGRAM OF A LECTURE ON POE, WITH ILLUSTRATIVE READINGS, BY MAJOR EVAN R. JONES, AMERICAN CONSUL FOR WALES, 1884 March 20.; [833]; Single sheet (Box 14)
    The lecture was sponsored by the Fine Art Loan Exhibition, New Public Hall, Cardiff, Wales.
  - " EDGAR A. POE AND HIS COLLEGE CONTEMPORARIES," by William McCreery Burwell, 1884 May 18.; [834]; 4 columns clipped from the New Orleans Times-Democrat (Box 14)
    Annotated by Ingram: "Mr. W. M. Burwell's few personal reminiscences are derived from T[homas] G[oode] Tucker's highly imaginative remembrances."
  - "POE'S FIRST BOOK," by George Birdley, 1884 June 15.; [835]; 1 1/4 columns clipped from the Richmond Dispatch, reprinted from the Current (Box 14)
    Attributes to Poe authorship of verses entitled "The Skeleton Hand" and "The Magician," which were printed in the Boston Yankee in 1829.
  - "A QUESTION OF AUTHORSHIP," letter to the Editor by John H. Ingram, 1884 July 3.; [836]; 1/4 column clipped from the Richmond Dispatch (Box 14)
    Ingram takes exception to George Birdley's attributing "The Skeleton Hand" and "The Magician" to Poe [Item 835].
  - "POE IN PARIS, " by Lewis Rosenthal, 1884 August.; [837]; Pp. 174-179 clipped from the Manhattan Illustrated Monthly Magazine (Box 14)
    Surveys Poe's popularity in France: "the literature of the United States... is, in our time, represented there by Poe, one of the most gifted, if one of the least distinctively national, of American writers."
  - "MAJOR JONES ON EDGAR ALLAN POE, " unsigned, 1884 December 9.; [838]; 1 column clipped from the London Daily Express (Box 14)
    Major Evan R. Jones, American Consul for Wales, offered a favorable account of Poe and paid tribute to Ingram for rescuing his reputation from "the odium that for twenty-five years had been cast upon it by his American biographers."
  - "POE: THE POET AND THE CRITIC," by Walter L. Sawyer, 1884 December 25.; [839]; Pp. 304-305 clipped from the Index (Box 14)
    Eulogistic paper read before the Northern and Southern Club at Portland, ME, 22 October 1884.
  - "SEQUEL TO'THE RAVEN'," by R. Allston Lavender, Jr., 1884.; [840]; 9 8-line stanzas clipped from the Funny Folks Annual (Box 14)
    Lavender is reported to have been "a maniac in the lunatic asylum at Raleigh, NC. He fancied that it was dictated by the spirit of Edgar A. Poe. "
  - "EIN DICHTERLEBEN," by John H. Ingram, translated by Leopold Katscher, 1884.; [841]; Pp. 26-39 clipped from Der Salon fuer Literatur, Kunst und Gesellschaft, VII (Box 14)
    In German. Critical-biographical sketch of Poe.
  - NOTICE OF THE TALES BY EDGAR ALLAN POE; POEMS AND ESSAYS BY EDGAR ALLAN POE, EDITED BY JOHN H. INGRAM, by Leopold Katscher, 1884.; [842]; P. 237 clipped from Die Gegenwart (Box 14)
    This volume was published by the Tauchnitz Press, Leipzig.
  - REVIEW OF THE TALES AND POEMS OF EDGAR ALLAN POE; WITH BIOGRAPHICAL ESSAY BY JOHN H. INGRAM, unsigned, 1884.; [843]; 1/2 column clipped from an unidentified newspaper (Box 14)
    This edition, in four volumes, was published in London by John C. Nimmo.
  - "A NEW POEM SAID TO BE BY POE," by "Frantic Jerry Foodle", ante 1885.; [844]; 7 8-line stanzas clipped from the Daily Graphic, reprinted from the Looking Glass (Box 14)
    The "new poem" is a parody of "The Raven" entitled "The Demon of the Doldrums."
  - "EDGARD POE," by Leo Quesnel, ante 1885.; [845]; Pp. 156-157 clipped from Le Muse Artistique et Littraire (Box 14)
    In French. Brief biographical sketch of Poe and an explanation of "The Raven."
  - "LAID BY THE POET'S SIDE," unsigned, 1885 January 20.; [846]; 1/2 column clipped from the Baltimore Sun (Box 14)
    Account of the reinterment of Virginia Clemm Poe by Poe's side in Westminster Churchyard in Baltimore on 19 January.
  - " EDGAR ALLAN POE, " by Emile Hennequin, 1885 January 25.; [847]; Pp. 24-56 clipped from La Revue Contemporaine, I (Box 14)
    A critical study.
  - PARODIES OF THE WORKS OF ENGLISH AND AMERICAN AUTHORS, collected and annotated by Walter Hamilton, 1885 January, March, April.; [848]; Vol. II, pts. 14, 16, 17 (Box 14)
    Parodies of many of Poe's poems. Ingram contributed a number of these, as well as many of the notes, especially those on "The Fire Fiend."
  - "WOODBERRY'S LIFE OF POE," unsigned, 1885 March 25.; [849]; 1/4 column clipped from the Lowell Morning Mail, reprinted from the Worcester Daily Times (Box 14)
    A review of George E. Woodberry's Edgar Allan Poe, a volume in the American Men of Letters Series, published by Houghton Mifflin Company. The reviewer finds the book, "considered as a biography," to be "beneath the standard which critical opinion long ago fixed for works of this sort; judged as a whole it is beneath contempt."
  - "MANUSCRIPT OF POE," unsigned, 1885 March.; [849-a]; Pp. 249-250 clipped from the American Antiquarian (Box 14)
    J. W. Johnston of Lancaster, PA, at one time the owner of the MS. of "The Murders in the Rue Morgue," relates the numerous close calls the MS. had with fire and loss. The MS. is now the property of George W. Childs.
  - "THE ACTORS HONOR POE," unsigned, 1885 May 5.; [850]; 4 columns clipped from the New York World (Box 15)
    Presentation ceremonies of the Poe Memorial to the Metropolitan Museum of Art on 4 May 1885. Annotated by Ingram.
  - "MORE PITY FOR POOR POE," unsigned, 1885 May 5.; [851]; 1/3 column clipped from the New York World (Box 15)
    Notice of the unveiling of the actors' monument to Poe at the Metropolitan Museum of Art in New York City.
  - "AN UNCANNY STORY OF ANNABEL LEE," unsigned, 1885 June 6.; [852]; Paragraph clipped from the Detroit Free Press (Box 15)
    Story of a New York gentleman ( William F. Gill ) having removed the bones of Virginia Clemm Poe from the Fordham cemetery and kept them in his home in New York City for two years before they were finally brought to Baltimore and reinterred by Poe's side.
  - "WHO MURDERED MARY ROGERS ?" by W. A. Croffut, and "WHERE POE WROTE'THE RAVEN'," unsigned, 1885 June 13.; [853]; 2 columns and an attached paragraph clipped from the Detroit Free Press (Box 15)
    The first item surveys the Mary Rogers case and Poe's connection with it. The second reports that Dr. John J. Moran believes he has identified the house where Poe wrote "The Raven."
  - "THE GHOST OF MARIE ROGET," unsigned, 1885 October 16.; [854]; 1/2 column clipped from the New York Sun (Box 15)
    Report that the ghost of Mary Rogers appeared at a seance.
  - "POE THE POET," unsigned, 1885 November 29.; [855]; 11/4 columns clipped from the Richmond State (Box 15)
    Reports James Albert Clarke's reminiscences of Poe at the University of Virginia and David Bridges' recollections of Poe's early days in Richmond.
  - " EDGAR ALLAN POE, " by M. W. H., 1885.; [856]; 3/4 column clipped from an unidentified newspaper (Box 15)
    Laudatory review of George E. Woodberry's Edgar Allan Poe.
  - A DEFENSE OF EDGAR ALLAN POE, by John J. Moran, M.D., 1885.; [857]; 88 pp. (Box 15)
    Published by William F. Boogher, Washington, DC, this booklet is heavily annotated by Ingram.
  - PHOTOGRAPH OF EDMUND CLARENCE STEDMAN, ca. 1885.; [858]; Clipped from an unidentified newspaper. (Box 15)
  - REVIEW OF THE RAVEN BY EDGAR ALLAN POE; WITH LITERARY AND HISTORICAL COMMENTARY BY JOHN H. INGRAM, unsigned, 1886 February 27.; [859]; P. 3 clipped from the Free Press (Box 15)
    Favorable review.
  - POE'S ALLEGED AUTHORSHIP OF "LEONAINIE," unsigned, 1886 April 28.; [860]; Paragraph clipped from the Daily News (Box 15)
    Repeats stories from the Critic (New York) and the Kokomo Dispatch (IN).
  - " EDGAR ALLAN POE, " unsigned, 1886 December 26.; [861]; Paragraph clipped from Lloyd's Weekly London Newspaper (Box 15)
    Review of the reissue of Ingram's two-volume Edgar Allan Poe: His Life, Letters and Opinions in a single volume in 1886 by Minerva Library of Famous Books. [This reissue was widely hailed and reviewed as a "revised" edition, when actually only a very few additions were made to its bibliography, and the index had to be remade to conform to the new pagination. Even such an able Poe scholar as Killis Campbell spoke of Ingram's "enlarged" biography, when such was not, in fact, the case.]
  - REVIEW OF EDGAR ALLAN POE: HIS LIFE, LETTERS AND OPINIONS, BY JOHN H. INGRAM, unsigned, 1886 December 28.; [862]; Paragraph clipped from the London Daily Times (Box 15)
    Reviewer criticizes the "charitable shortsightedness" of Ingram's efforts at a "cleansing" biography.
  - REVIEW OF EDGAR ALLAN POE: HIS LIFE, LETTERS AND OPINIONS, BY JOHN H. INGRAM, unsigned, 1886.; [863]; 2 paragraphs clipped from an unidentified English newspaper (Box 15)
    Generally favorable toward Ingram's efforts to present an accurate picture of Poe.
  - "POE, THE CIPHER WIZARD," letter to the Editor by John H. Ingram, post 1886.; [864]; Paragraph clipped from an unidentified English newspaper (Box 15)
    Ingram complains that the newspaper's recent account of "Poe, the Cipher Wizard" can be found in his own 1886 Edgar Allan Poe: His Life, Letters and Opinions. Ingram adds that "our American cousins are very fond of extracts from my work; if they would only quote correctly, and without adornments, I should feel more gratified."
  - REVIEW OF EDGAR ALLAN POE: HIS LIFE, LETTERS AND OPINIONS, BY JOHN H. INGRAM, unsigned, 1887 January 10.; [865]; Pp. 34-35 clipped from Allen's Indian Mail. (Box 15)
  - REVIEW OF EDGAR ALLAN POE: HIS LIFE, LETTERS AND OPINIONS, BY JOHN H. INGRAM, unsigned, 1887 April 16.; [866]; Paragraph clipped from Vanity Fair (Box 15)
  - " EDGAR ALLAN POE, " unsigned, 1887 September 2.; [867]; Pp. 205-206 clipped from the Literary World (Box 15)
    Review of Ingram's Edgar Allan Poe: His Life, Letters and Opinions.
  - "POE'S FIRST AND LAST LOVE," unsigned, 1887 February 11.; [867-a]; 1/2 column clipped from an unidentified Richmond newspaper (Box 15)
    Obituary of Sarah Elmira Royster Shelton, who died in Richmond on 10 February.
  - " EDGAR ALLAN POE, " unsigned, 1887 July-December.; [867-b]; Pp. 248-252 clipped from Great Thoughts from Master Minds (Box 15)
    A critical-biographical article based upon Rufus Griswold's Memoir of Poe.
  - BOOKSELLER'S ADVERTISEMENT OF LA CITE EN LA MER, POEME D' EDGAR POE, ILLUSTRE ET TRADUIT PAR MM. EDOUARD MANET ET STEPHANE MALLARME and LES POEMS D' EDGAR POE, TRADUCTION EN PROSE, PREFACE DE STEPHANE MALLARME, 1888.; [868]; 1 p., Librairie de l'Eau-Forte (Box 15)
  - "POE AS A REPEATER, unsigned [ Eugene L. Didier ], 1889 January 20.; [869]; 1 column clipped from the Richmond Critic (Box 15)
    A San Francisco Bohemian, formerly a Baltimorean, tells a reporter that he was an eye-witness when Poe was drugged, cooped, and voted thirty-one times before he died.
  - STORY OF POE'S BEING DRUGGED, COOPED, AND VOTED, unsigned, 1889 February 16.; [870]; Pp. 219-220 clipped from the London Weekly Register (Box 15)
    Cites story in the New York Sun about a San Francisco Bohemian, formerly a Baltimorean, who claims to have been a witness.
  - "POE'S LAST WILD FANCY," unsigned, 1889 March 3.; [871]; 2 columns clipped from the New York World (Box 15)
    John Sartain tells a story of Poe's last visit to Philadelphia, in the summer of 1849, and of his imprisonment. He also relates a story called "The Three Visions," which Poe told to him.
  - "AN OLD POEM BY POE," unsigned, 1889 March 15.; [872]; 1/3 column clipped from the Richmond Times, reprinted from the Kokomo Dispatch (IN) (Box 15)
    Repeats the hoax perpetrated by James Whitcomb Riley in 1877.
  - "SHARPS AND FLATS," unsigned, 1889 April 12.; [873]; 1 1/4 columns clipped from the Chicago Daily Times (Box 15)
    Surveys the relationship between Poe and E. H. N. Patterson in their plans to establish the Stylus.
  - "OH TEMPORA! OH MORES!," unsigned, 1889 October.; [874]; No Name Magazine, I, 1-2 (Box 15)
    Prints the text of the poem and furnishes an account of its background. Eugene L. Didier edited this magazine.
  - " EDGAR ALLAN POE. A SKETCH," by X. E. R., 1890 March.; [875]; The Literary Light, III, 35-38 (Box 15)
    Surveys Poe's life and work and applauds efforts to redeem his name.
  - "A BOX OF AUTOGRAPHS," by Richard Henry Stoddard, 1891 February.; [876]; Pp. 213-227 clipped from Scribner's Magazine (Box 15)
    Brief, harshly derogatory comment on Poe's life and writings. Poe's "To Zante" is reproduced in facsimile on p. 224.
  - "POE'S LIFE IN FORDHAM, " unsigned, 1891 February 16.; [877]; 2 columns clipped from the New Orleans Times-Democrat. Reprinted from the New York Times (Box 15)
    Reports the death of Reverend Edward Doucet, S. J., and memories of Poe by Father Schully, George Pope Morris, and John B. Haskins. William F. Gill has bought the Poe Cottage.
  - "POE'S COTTAGE IS SAFE," unsigned, 1891 August 17.; [878]; Paragraph clipped from an unidentified newspaper (Box 15)
    Clyde W. Bryson has bought the Poe Cottage from the heirs of the old Rose Hill estate and has set apart $50,000 to keep the house and grounds in order.
  - "RECOLLECTIONS OF EDGAR ALLEN [sic] POE, " by Howard Paul, 1892 September.; [880]; Pp. 22-25 clipped from Lambert's Monthly (Box 15)
    This article had been printed in Munsey's Magazine, VII (August 1892), 554-558. Ingram's annotation: "All lies."
  - "THE OLD MAN ELOQUENT. GABRIEL HARRISON'S PORTRAIT OF EDGAR ALLEN [sic] POE, " unsigned, 1892 ante December.; [880-a]; 1 column clipped from an unidentified newspaper (Box 15)
    Description of Harrison and his studio. Harrison's portrait of Poe is now in the Brooklyn Historical Society Library.
  - "FIGHT WITH EDGAR ALLEN [sic] POE, " unsigned, 1894 March 3.; [881]; 1/3 column clipped from the Washington News (Box 15)
    Thomas Dunn English tells a reporter about a fight he had with Poe. Ingram's annotation: "A pack of self-proved lies."
  - " EDGAR A. POE. LETTERS RELATING TO HIS LIFE WHEN HE WAS IN BALTIMORE AND RICHMOND, " unsigned, 1894 August 5.; [882]; 3 columns clipped from the Baltimore Sunday News (Box 15)
    Defensive of Rufus W. Griswold, the article is based upon George E. Woodberry's "Poe in the South: Selections from the Correspondence of Edgar Allan Poe, " Century Magazine, N.S., XXVI (August 1894), 572-583, 725-737, 854-866, and reprints letters from Poe to Thomas W. White, John P. Kennedy, and Nathaniel Beverly Tucker, and a letter from James Kirke Paulding to Thomas W. White.
  - "POE IN PHILADELPHIA: SELECTIONS FROM THE CORRESPONDENCE OF EDGAR ALLAN POE, " edited by George E. Woodberry, 1894 September.; [883]; Pp. 725-732 clipped from the Century Magazine, N.S., XXVI (September 1894) (Box 15)
    Letters to Poe from William E. Burton (10 May 1839), Washington Irving (6 November 1839), N. P. Willis (30 November 1841), Charles Dickens (6 March 1842), Frederick W. Thomas (20 May, 1 July, 30 August 1841; 21 May 1842), Robert Tyler (31 March 1842). Letters from Poe to Philip Pendleton Cooke (21 September 1839), Henry Wadsworth Longfellow (22 June 1841), Frederick W. Thomas (23 November 1840, 25 May 1842).
  - " EDGAR ALLAN POE. THE FIRST AND LAST BURIALS OF THE FAMOUS POET," unsigned [ Eugene L. Didier ], 1894 December 30.; [884]; 1 1/2 columns clipped from the Baltimore Sunday News (Box 15)
    Striking contrast between the burial of Poe on 9 October 1849 and the pageantry that accompanied his exhumation and reburial on 17 November 1875. Identifies persons present at Poe's first burial.
  - "MEMORIES OF POE," unsigned, 1895 February 10.; [885]; 2 1/2 columns clipped from the Richmond Dispatch (Box 15)
    Review of Volume I of The Works of Edgar Allan Poe, edited by Edmund Clarence Stedman and George Edward Woodberry, 10 volumes (Chicago: 1894-95).
  - "WHO WROTE'THE RAVEN' -- POE OR HIRST?" by Benjamin Blake Minor, 1895 February 17.; [886]; 4 columns clipped from the Richmond Times (Box 15)